<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Make the Web Fun Again on Limity Jsme My</title><link>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/</link><description>Recent content in Make the Web Fun Again on Limity Jsme My</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 14:49:14 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fourth Event</title><link>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/events/fourth-event/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 14:49:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/events/fourth-event/</guid><description>&lt;p>This place has been inhabited since ancient times. This was proven when the settlement &amp;lsquo;Valy&amp;rsquo; (&amp;lsquo;Валы&amp;rsquo;) was found here on the river Islach. In the 16th century these ruins were used as a platform for feudal castle building. The Rakov castle can be found on the map created by Tomash Makovski in 1613. In the 14th century documents, settlements near contemporary Rakov are mentioned for the first time. Rakov itself is mentioned in 15th century chronicles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Third Event</title><link>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/events/third-event/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 14:49:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/events/third-event/</guid><description>&lt;p>Grobler scored on his international debut against Zimbabwe on 15 November 2011. Born in Sandton, Grobler is the son of former Moroka Swallows player Les Grobler.[6] Rakaw (Belarusian: Ракаў Rakaw; Russian: Раков Rakov; Polish: Raków) is an urban settlement in Valozhyn Raion, Minsk Region, Belarus.[1] It stands on the river Islach 40 km (25 mi) from Volozhin and 39 km (24 mi) from Minsk, the capital of Belarus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First event</title><link>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/events/first-event/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 14:49:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/events/first-event/</guid><description>&lt;p>Bradley Allan Grobler (born January 25, 1988) is a South African footballer who plays as a striker for Premier Soccer League club SuperSport United and the South African national team.[2] Grobler attended Benoni High School and plied his trade as a junior at both Boksburg FC and BK Callies just outside Johannesburg. Bradley started his professional football career at Platinum Stars. After a four-year stint at Stars, he moved to Turkish second division side Göztepe A.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Second Event</title><link>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/events/second-event/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 14:49:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/events/second-event/</guid><description>&lt;p>On 26 June 2012, Grobler joined Premier Soccer League side Ajax Cape Town on a four-year deal.[5] He has scored over 8 goals against Orlando Pirates, while at Supersport United. In early September 2019, Bradley Grobler signed for Forest Green Rovers on a free transfer. During his short time at the club, Grobler scored 15 goals in only 9 league games, helping Rovers to top the League Two table before Christmas without dropping a single point.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About us</title><link>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/about-us/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 20:40:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/about-us/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="our-history">Our history&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We consider February 6th, 2015 the official founding date of the &amp;ldquo;We are the limits&amp;rdquo; movement. That was the day that, in almost 20 cities, hundreds of people took to the streets to protest the proposition of then-minister of industry and commerce Jan Mladek to break the ecological limits of brown coal extraction in the Bílina and ČSA mines. The expansion of the ČSA mine would have also meant the destruction of the town of Horní Jiřetín , which lay at the edge of the existing mine. Those protests brought the issues of coal extraction and burning and their impact on the environment and climate into the public debate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We organized a similar action in the same year in June. We got over 20 cities, both from Czechia and abroad, to join us, and over a thousand people took to the streets. Most of them were from Litvínov, Prague, Brno, and of course Horní Jiřetín. Thoughout the campaign to preserve the limits of extraction, we also organized a few happenings. The best one was in front of the house of one of the coal barons, Jan Dienstl, in Třebívlice, where we started his morning by playing a loud recording of an excavator at work. The success of this campaign may be evidenced by the fact that later an angry Dienstl called one of our members and asked us to leave him alone. We didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The campaign to preserve the limits ended with a demonstration at the government retreat in Ústí nad Labe, where the ministers approved breaking the limits of extraction in the Bílina mine. Through our collective effort, we saved Jiřetín, but the post-communist consensus about extraction limits was no more and we entered a new era. After this partially successful campaign, we decided to continue and transform ourselves into a climate justice movement. This was one of the reasons that we, along with other organizations, organized a climate march the evening before an important climate meeting in Paris. The very first Czech climate march attracted around 500 people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of us were at the critical climate conference in Paris in person, including actions and protests. The Paris conference wasn&amp;rsquo;t very pivotal in terms of climate protection, but was pivotal in terms of defining our tactics as a movement. From Paris we know that we cannot trust politicians, because their thirty year effort led to an agreement that even if fully honoured would mean an average warming of the planet of 2.7 degrees compared to preindustrial conditions. We therefore entered 2016 with the understanding that we ourselves have to be the limits of the fossil fuel industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="2016">2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The most important month for our development as a movement was May. We decided to organize a bus trip from Czechia to the largest climate justice direct action - Ende Gelände in German Lausitz. We managed to get about 70 people to join us. They joined with around 4,000 brave people who blocked the excavators at Welzow Sud with their bodies. For three days, we worked together to block the excavators in the mine, as well as blocking the tracks to the Schwarze pumpe coal-powered electric plant. The atmosphere of the German Climate camp was so inspiring to us that we decided to have our own Climatecamp in Czechia in the summer of 2016. We also started to define ourselves as a non-hierarchical open movement and started to organize our own open plenums.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="2017">2017&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In the first half of the year we organized a few smaller happenings that were meant to draw attention to the most critical problems regarding the excavation and burning of coal. One of the most successful was the die-in at the local government building in Pardubice, which was meant to draw attention to the slowness of the officials who participated in breaking the rules when modernizing the Chvaletice electrical plant. We also joined the campaign against the privatization of the Počerady electrical plant into the hands of the coal barons Tykač and Dienstl, who would have continued operating it for the next decades. Thanks in part to public pressure, we were able to stop the privatization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In June, after a month of organizing, we had our first Climatecamp, which took place symbolically in the town of Horní Jiřetín, a municipality that had spent years defending itself against the demolition that would have resulted had the expansion of the ČSA mine been granted. For five days, our Climatecamp became an open space to share experiences and information with the help of workshops and lectures, and an inspiration for a sustainable lifestile. The camp was attended by around 250 people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After 3 days full of talks and workshops, our participants joined the protests against the coal industry. First, we went on a march around the boundary of the ČSA mine, to show that the limits of extraction aren&amp;rsquo;t possible to break. After that, 140 of us chose to practice civil disobedience and blocked the excavators in the Bílina coal mine. The first year of Climatecamp was very successful and was a good sign for the future. The climate justice movement was beginning to grow. We also joined two Ende Gelände actions that took place in July and October in German Rhineland.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="2018">2018&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>During the next summer, we decided to take part in a divestmant campaign. As a show of solidarity with people from Hrádek nad Nisou, who are in danger of having insufficient water due to the expansion of the giant nearby Turów mine, which extracts water at the expense of the nearby residents. Together with other organizations we formed a human chain at the Czech-German-Polish border, where together with the locals we showed that the Turów mine needs to end, both for climate reasons and for water reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In May we organized 14 days for climate. We were joined by various other organizations and collectives through smaller, local actions that drew attention to the climate crisis threat and the need to quickly get rid of our dependence on coal and other fossil fuels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, our main action was the third year of Climatecamp, which took place this time near the Chvaletice coal plant. The owners of the mine were asking for an exception to the emission limits, in order to keep polluting the air and deepening the climate crisis. Hundreds of people blocked the entry to the plant itself, where we slept for three nights and requested the end of its operations. The end of coal needs to happen now if we are to avoid the main impacts of the climate crisis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In November we continued with a direct action in Most, where we adorned the house of the owner of the Chvaletice    Severní Energetická plant with banners reading &amp;ldquo;The end of coal, without exception&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Seven - we ruin the climate day and night&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="2020">2020&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The future is unwritten. Come write it with us. Join the climate justice movement and help us end the era of coal. Because until the last coal plant and last mine is closed, we are the limits!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Get involved</title><link>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/get-involved/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 20:40:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/get-involved/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Be a limit of the fossil fuel industry!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are a non-hierarchical, open organization. This means that we don&amp;rsquo;t have bosses or managers - we make all of our decisions collectively, anyone can get involved and anyone - from cooks to photographers &amp;ndash; can find a way to contribute. Once every two months or so, we hold an open plenum, where we decide on the most critical matters regarding the movement. The easiest way to get involved is to join one of our working groups, which are specifically focused on different areas of our activity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="join-a-working-group">Join a working group.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We have the following long-term working groups:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="building-the-movement">Building the movement&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The goal of the &amp;ldquo;Building the movement&amp;rdquo; group is to gain the support of different parts of society for our activities, whether it&amp;rsquo;s specifically getting ready for Climatecamps, recruiting new folks to join us, or other work. Here, you can learn to organize talks and screenings, find out what it&amp;rsquo;s like to speak publicly, or come up with creative engagement strategies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="typical-tasks-in-this-group">Typical tasks in this group:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Organize a talk, help distribute leaflets and posters, come up with your own geocache for the geocaching project.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="communication">Communication&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The communication group takes care of all the online and written communications of the We are the Limits movement. This includes moderating our social media and website, coming up with communication strategies for the whole movement as well as for individual actions, making graphics, flyers, posters, or texts, sending our newsletter, coming up with our fundraising campaign, public appeals, interfacing with media, writing news releases, working on press conferences. For Climatecamp we prepare a camp brochure, media strategy, or a press conference for media. In this group you can learn to write impactful texts, make graphics, manage social media or improve your ability to communicate with journalists.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="typical-tasks-in-this-group-1">Typical tasks in this group:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Take care of our Facebook/Twitter/Instagram for two weeks, do the graphic design for our Climatecamp posters, write a press release, write a newsletter, come up with a finance campaign (in collaboration with our Finance team).&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="law">Law&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Our law group takes care of everything relating to the law and the legal dimensions of our work. They create    legal analyses, train folks before our actions, provide legal advice during actions, provide legal counsel and assistance after our actions. They also communicate with the police. In this group you don&amp;rsquo;t need a law degree - much of the work is coordination. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn here how the law works and you&amp;rsquo;ll improve your ability to communicate with lawyers and police officers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="typical-tasks-in-this-group-2">Typical tasks in this group:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Answer questions in our law emails, communicate with our lawyer, facilitate a legal education workshop.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="finance">Finance&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The financial group tries to raise funds for our activities, tracks them (including creating budgets, accounting, cashflow), communicates with donors (people and institutions) and encourages a culture of responsible finance management in the movement. In this group you can learn to manage money, build our budget, or write grants.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="typical-tasks-in-this-group-3">Typical tasks in this group:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Write a grant for a non-profit, come up with a fundraising campaign, track our accounting and expense sheets&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="logistics">Logistics&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The logistics group manages all our materials and ensures a safe Climatecamp. It forms in the weeks and months before Climatecamp and slowly absorbs most of the members of the movement. The logistics group ensures water, electricity, toilets, showers, tents, lighting, etc. In this group you can learn plenty of practical skills, that you will use even in daily life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="typical-tasks-in-this-group-4">Typical tasks in this group:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Figure out how to get water to the Climatecamp, coordinate finding tents for Climatecamp, come up with a ground plan for setting up tents in Climatecamp&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="chillax">Chillax&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The chillax group aims to monitor the mental and physical state of our members. The fight for climate justice is a long haul, and so the chillax group tries to come up with ways to make our activism sustainable. They have regular meetings, where we talk about things that bug us in the movement. They help people, who for whatever reason don&amp;rsquo;t feel well, and try to come up with strategies to change the world and have fun doing it. In this group you&amp;rsquo;ll learn a lot about techniques to make activism as sustainable and pleasant as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="typical-tasks-in-this-group-5">Typical tasks in this group:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Organize a meeting, come up with a way to energise our plena, organize a trip for people from the movement.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="safety">Safety&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The safety group ensures that the movement is safe from negative influences from outside of our organization. It helps set up safety rules, organizes regular trainings in cybersafety (so-called cryptoparties) and at Climatecamp it ensures the safety of all participants. In this group you can improve your ability to change the world without being stopped by a higher power (we also call them the blue team sometimes&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="typical-tasks-in-this-group-6">Typical tasks in this group:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Organize a cryptoparty, come up with rules for safe behaviour in the group&amp;rsquo;s communication channels.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="strategy">Strategy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The strategy group aims to follow events concerning coal and prepare materials for our strategic decisionmaking. It follows live issues, that we can be active in, and communicates with our allies. In this group you can learn a lot about the coal situation in Czechia and try out strategic thinking in the context of an organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="typical-tasks-in-this-group-7">Typical tasks in this group:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Join the call of the coalition against the sale of the Počerady electrical plant and make notes, follow the developments in the issue of the exception for limits of pollution for the Chvaletice coal plant.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="engaging-new-people">Engaging new people&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Our goal is for the climate justice movement in Czechia to grow. It&amp;rsquo;s therefore critical to know how to engage new people in our movement. The engagement group therefore takes care of people who want to join the movement. It gives them all the relevant information, helps them feel welcome at our plenum, or connects them with working groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="typical-tasks-in-this-group-8">Typical tasks in this group:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Organize a talk at the beginning of the plenum about how the movement works and how to behave at the plenum, answer emails of people who want to join us&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="come-to-the-plenum">Come to the plenum&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A plenum happens once every month and a half in different parts of Czechia. Look at our Facebook and come to the next one. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have Facebook, sign up for our newsletter on our website.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="make-a-local-group">Make a local group&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In Brno and Prague there are regular meetings of local groups. You can find out more about them on Facebook. We also have many members in northern Bohemia, in Ostrava, Olomouc, Jihlava and other cities. We can connect you with them, or help you organize something where nothing exists yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="be-online">Be online&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Follow us on Facebook Instagram, and Twitter and share our content. Join the (Czech-speaking) Protizměnám klimatu, za klimatickou spravedlnost! group on&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://limityjsmemy.github.io/limityjsmemy.cz/en/contact/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>